/**
 * Author: @Manuel G. Sintos
 * Date: Nov 27, 2023, 1:11 PM
 *
 */

const data_03 = [
	{
	    id: 0,
	    question: "Which of the following is a fundamental human right recognized by the Philippine Constitution?",
	    choices: [
	        "The right to own a car",
	        "The right to free education",
	        "The right to a high-paying job",
	        "The right to live in a mansion",
	        "The right to eat at fancy restaurants"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "The right to free education",
	    explanation: "According to Article XIV, Section 1 of the Philippine Constitution, 'The State shall protect and promote the right of all citizens to quality education at all levels, and shall take appropriate steps to make such education accessible to all.' This means that every person has the right to access quality education, and that the government should take steps to make education available to all."
	},
    {
        id: 1,
        question: "What is the main purpose of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights?",
        choices: [
            "To provide a framework for global governance",
            "To outline fundamental human rights that should be protected",
            "To establish laws for space exploration",
            "To regulate international trade",
            "To set standards for environmental protection"
        ],
        correct_ans: "To outline fundamental human rights that should be protected",
        explanation: "The Universal Declaration of Human Rights was adopted by the United Nations General Assembly in 1948 with the aim of outlining the fundamental human rights that should be universally protected."
    },

    {
        id: 2,
        question: "What does the right to peace entail according to the United Nations?",
        choices: [
            "The right to live in a world free from war and violence",
            "The right to own a car",
            "The right to a high-paying job",
            "The right to live in a mansion",
            "The right to eat at fancy restaurants"
        ],
        correct_ans: "The right to live in a world free from war and violence",
        explanation: "According to the United Nations, the right to peace entails every person's right to enjoy peace such that all human rights are promoted and protected, and development is fully realized."
    },
    {
        id: 3,
        question: "Which document outlines the basic civil liberties and political rights of individuals?",
        choices: [
            "The Paris Agreement",
            "The Geneva Convention",
            "The International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights",
            "The Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons",
            "The Montreal Protocol"
        ],
        correct_ans: "The International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights",
        explanation: `The International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights is a key international human rights treaty, providing a range of protections for civil and political rights.`
    },

    {
        id: 4,
        question: "Which international treaty was adopted to enhance the implementation of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights?",
        choices: [
            "The Paris Agreement",
            "The Geneva Convention",
            "The International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights",
            "The Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons",
            "The Montreal Protocol"
        ],
        correct_ans: "The International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights",
        explanation: "The International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights is a multilateral treaty adopted by the United Nations General Assembly to enhance the implementation of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights."
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "In 2017, which city in the Philippines was placed under martial law due to the conflict with extremist groups?",
      "choices": [
        "Cebu City",
        "Quezon City",
        "Davao City",
        "Marawi City",
        "Manila City"
      ],
      "correct_ans": "Marawi City",
      "explanation": "In 2017, Marawi City in the Philippines was placed under martial law due to the conflict with extremist groups, particularly the Maute group."
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "Which Filipino journalist and human rights advocate was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2021 for her efforts to protect freedom of expression?",
      "choices": [
        "Maria Ressa",
        "Leila de Lima",
        "Jose Maria Sison",
        "Rodrigo Duterte",
        "Ferdinand Marcos"
      ],
      "correct_ans": "Maria Ressa",
      "explanation": "Maria Ressa, a prominent Filipino journalist, and human rights advocate, was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2021 for her courageous efforts to protect freedom of expression and press freedom."
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Which United Nations Special Rapporteur on extrajudicial, summary, or arbitrary executions investigated human rights violations in the Philippines during the presidency of Rodrigo Duterte?",
      "choices": [
        "Kofi Annan",
        "Agnes Callamard",
        "Ban Ki-moon",
        "Ant√≥nio Guterres",
        "Aung San Suu Kyi"
      ],
      "correct_ans": "Agnes Callamard",
      "explanation": "Agnes Callamard, the United Nations Special Rapporteur on extrajudicial, summary, or arbitrary executions, conducted an investigation into human rights violations in the Philippines during the presidency of Rodrigo Duterte."
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Which Philippine president declared martial law in 1972, leading to a period of authoritarian rule?",
      "choices": [
        "Fidel V. Ramos",
        "Corazon Aquino",
        "Gloria Macapagal-Arroyo",
        "Ferdinand Marcos",
        "Benigno Aquino III"
      ],
      "correct_ans": "Ferdinand Marcos",
      "explanation": "Ferdinand Marcos declared martial law in 1972, leading to a period of authoritarian rule in the Philippines that lasted until 1981."
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "Which Filipino human rights advocate and former senator was detained for her alleged involvement in illegal drug activities, drawing international attention to her case?",
      "choices": [
        "Maria Ressa",
        "Leila de Lima",
        "Ninoy Aquino",
        "Ferdinand Marcos",
        "Benigno Aquino III"
      ],
      "correct_ans": "Leila de Lima",
      "explanation": "Leila de Lima, a prominent Filipino human rights advocate and former senator, was detained for her alleged involvement in illegal drug activities, drawing international attention to her case and concerns about political persecution."
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "What 2016 government anti-drug campaign has faced significant international scrutiny and criticism due to allegations of human rights abuses, including extrajudicial killings?",
      "choices": [
          "Oplan Bayanihan",
          "Oplan Sagip Bayan",
          "Oplan Bantay Laya",
          "Oplan Double Barrel",
          "Oplan Tokhang"
      ],
      "correct_ans": "Oplan Tokhang",
      "explanation": "Oplan Tokhang is a government anti-drug campaign that began in 2016 and has faced significant international scrutiny and criticism for alleged human rights abuses, particularly extrajudicial killings."
    },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which senator and critic of President Rodrigo Duterte has been a vocal advocate for human rights, including opposition to extrajudicial killings in the context of the government's anti-drug campaign?",
    "choices": [
        "Imee Marcos",
        "Alan Peter Cayetano",
        "Panfilo Lacson",
        "Antonio Trillanes IV",
        "Bong Go"
    ],
    "correct_ans": "Antonio Trillanes IV",
    "explanation": "Antonio Trillanes IV is a senator and critic of President Rodrigo Duterte who has been a vocal advocate for human rights, including his opposition to extrajudicial killings in the context of the government's anti-drug campaign."
  },
  {
      id: 12,
      question: "In 2016, Which human rights issue in the Philippines has been a significant concern, often associated with armed conflict and social unrest?",
      choices: [
          "Freedom of Speech",
          "Right to Education",
          "Extrajudicial Killings",
          "Right to Health",
          "Right to Adequate Housing"
      ],
      correct_ans: "Extrajudicial Killings",
      explanation: "Extrajudicial killings in the Philippines have been a pressing human rights issue, particularly in relation to the government's anti-drug campaign. These killings involve the unlawful execution of individuals suspected of involvement in the drug trade, often without due process or legal proceedings. This issue has drawn international attention and criticism due to its impact on the right to life and the rule of law."
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: "What is the term for the practice of granting pardon or amnesty to individuals involved in armed conflicts as a means of promoting peace and reconciliation?",
    choices: [
        "Extradition",
        "Reparations",
        "Amnesty",
        "Conscription",
        "Detente"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Amnesty",
    explanation: "Amnesty is the practice of granting pardon or forgiveness to individuals involved in armed conflicts, often as part of peace negotiations. It aims to promote reconciliation and end hostilities."
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: "In a presidential system of government, what does the term 'veto' refer to?",
    choices: [
        "A ceremonial act performed by the President during inaugurations",
        "The power of the President to reject or block legislation passed by the legislature",
        "A vote of confidence given by the legislature to the President",
        "A formal declaration of war by the President",
        "A presidential pardon granted to a convicted criminal"
    ],
    correct_ans: "The power of the President to reject or block legislation passed by the legislature",
    explanation: "In a presidential system of government, a 'veto' refers to the power of the President to reject or block legislation passed by the legislature. This is a constitutional check and balance that allows the executive branch to prevent certain bills from becoming law."
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: "Who holds the constitutional power to veto bills passed by the Congress?",
    choices: [
        "Supreme Court Justices",
        "Speaker of the House of Representatives",
        "President of the Senate",
        "Vice President",
        "President of the Philippines"
    ],
    correct_ans: "President of the Philippines",
    explanation: "In the Philippines, the President holds the constitutional power to veto bills passed by the Congress. This is an important part of the legislative process, allowing the executive to review and potentially reject proposed laws."
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: "When the President of the Philippines vetoes a bill, what majority vote is required in Congress to potentially override the veto and pass the bill into law?",
    choices: [
        "Simple majority",
        "Two-thirds majority",
        "Three-fourths majority",
        "Unanimous vote",
        "Majority in one house, unanimous in the other"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Two-thirds majority",
    explanation: "In the Philippines, to potentially override a presidential veto and pass the bill into law, a two-thirds majority vote is required in both houses of Congress (the House of Representatives and the Senate). This ensures a significant level of support for the bill."
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: "Which vulnerable group was highlighted as facing increased risks during the COVID-19 pandemic?",
    choices: [
        "Elderly population",
        "Government officials",
        "Business executives",
        "Foreign tourists",
        "Members of the military"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Elderly population",
    explanation: "In recent human rights news in the Philippines, the elderly population was highlighted as facing increased risks during the COVID-19 pandemic. They are particularly vulnerable to the health impacts of the virus."
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: "What major infrastructure project aims to connect the islands of Luzon, Visayas, and Mindanao through a series of bridges and tunnels?",
    choices: [
        "North-South Commuter Railway",
        "Skyway Extension Project",
        "Manila Baywalk Rehabilitation",
        "Davao City Bypass Road",
        "The 'Build, Build, Build' project"
    ],
    correct_ans: "The 'Build, Build, Build' project",
    explanation: "In recent Philippine news, the 'Build, Build, Build' project is a major infrastructure initiative aimed at connecting the islands of Luzon, Visayas, and Mindanao through a network of bridges and tunnels, promoting economic development and connectivity."
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: "What issue has been a subject of concern due to its impact on marine biodiversity and local communities?",
    choices: [
        "Rising air pollution",
        "Deforestation",
        "Illegal fishing practices",
        "Urbanization",
        "Wildlife trafficking"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Illegal fishing practices",
    explanation: "Recent environmental news in the Philippines has raised concerns about illegal fishing practices, which have detrimental effects on marine biodiversity and the livelihoods of local communities dependent on fishing."
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: "What major legislation was signed into law to strengthen the government's response to public health emergencies?",
    choices: [
        "Freedom of Information Act",
        "Universal Healthcare Act",
        "Anti-Terrorism Act",
        "Anti-Discrimination Act",
        "Divorce Law"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Universal Healthcare Act",
    explanation: "In recent political news in the Philippines, the Universal Healthcare Act was signed into law to strengthen the government's response to public health emergencies and improve healthcare access for all citizens."
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question: "In recent environmental news in the Philippines, what conservation efforts have been implemented to protect endangered species and their habitats?",
    choices: [
        "Building new shopping malls",
        "Expanding industrial zones",
        "Establishing wildlife reserves",
        "Increasing deforestation",
        "Promoting air pollution"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Establishing wildlife reserves",
    explanation: "Recent environmental news in the Philippines has highlighted the establishment of wildlife reserves and conservation efforts to protect endangered species and their habitats."
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Excessive use of force by policemen is popularly referred to as:",
    "choices": [
      "Survival tactics",
      "Police enforcement elective",
      "Police bodily harm",
      "Police Brutality",
      "Law enforcement overreach"
    ],
    "correct_ans": "Police Brutality",
    "explanation": "Excessive use of force by policemen is popularly referred to as ‚ÄúPolice Brutality‚Äù. This term is used to describe instances when law enforcement officers exercise more force than necessary in the line of duty. It‚Äôs a serious issue that is often discussed in the context of human rights and law enforcement ethics."
  }










];